Hitanshu Dhingra

+91-8448752091 | hitanshud9@gmail.com | Delhi, India

Summary

An experienced copywriter with a passion to explore the abyss of human desire. To seek out new ideas, executing them from the planning stage to fruition.

Combining **over 6 years of experience** and versatile skills in copywriting, content writing, content creation, editing, proofreading, and SEO.

Experience

Vermillion | Delhi

Copy Writer (full-time employee) | 06/2018 - 11/2019

- Crafted engaging copy for a variety of print and digital media, including brands like Patanjali and Berkowitz.
- Wrote content for websites, emails, press releases, newsletters, and other marketing collateral.
- · Managed multiple projects simultaneously and met tight deadlines.
- Learnt the tricks of the trade under the mentorship of highly skilled copywriters with over 20+ years of experience.

Freelance | Remote

Freelance Writer | 03/2020 - 01/2021

- Worked on various freelance gigs. (One-time projects)
- · Gained valuable experience in different niches
- · Worked for various clients across industries like finance, IT, education and web-development.
- Helped a few designers with their design ideas and mood board implementations.

Ghostwriter - Wellness Blog | Remote

Content Writer (contract role) | 04/2020 - 09/2021

- Private ghostwriting contract to compile content for client's Health & Wellness Blog/Website.
- Wrote Blogs/Articles on living better through a healthier lifestyle.
- Completed approx. 500 articles in under 1.5 years compared to the client's estimate of over 2 years.
- Exhibited an ability to single-handedly understand, research and compile information from professional studies to a layman-level explanation of the subject that can be understood by a base level reader.
- Exhibited the ability to see projects through to completion.

Digibots media | Delhi

Copy Writer (Full-time Contractor) | 03/2021 - 12/2023

- Researched and wrote copy for the client's social media platforms and advertising campaigns.
- Updated the agency's landing page and website.
- Crafted state-of-the-art webpage copy for Fashion Brand.
- Used the best SEO practices to increase visibility and engagement.
- Collaborated with graphic designers, marketing teams, and other stakeholders to ensure the quality of content and make the brand-voice spot on
- Helped onboard 2 clients through excellent presentation and communication skills
- Compiled content-calendars to organize content better providing a quick turn-around time with lower costs, helping the venture grow steadily.

Unibots Media | WFH, Delhi

Content Writer (Full-time Contractor) | 05/2024 - 09/2024

- · Wrote blogs for client websites and SEO purposes
- Averaged productivity at 6 articles/3000 words per day
- Integrated SEO keywords meaningfully driving upwards ranking
- Helped secure clearance for new websites by meeting Google AdSense Guidelines
- · Provided value needed for website clearance by Google AdSense

Skills

Copywriting, Expert Research, Expert Content Creation, Expert SEO, Expert Creativity, Expert Digital Marketing, Expert Attention to detail, Expert Storytelling, Expert Languages English, Native Speaker Hindi, Native Speaker

Education

SGTB Khalsa College, Delhi University | Dili English (Hons.) | 12/2017

IGNOU English (Hons.) | 12/2022

Online Portfolio Link

https://docs.google.com/document/d/1pGUULjqPzsdnCEwYiGvI1WjcUF2Y1qNjZeFXy8nZK8s/edit?usp=sharing https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ZfU8yx0OKJq5LblYKo5TfbzO0KaCq_4nDzEmBVEhRhl/edit?usp=sharing